A price behaves here will be distinctly different to many of these other candles.
Even that candle here, this candle will behave completely differently in terms of it's ticking, how it's ticking.
So you can see prices ticking down, down, it's low volume right now, down again, down again.
You get it, you see how it's ticking?
Yeah.
These will behave in a flat, the tickiness of them will be quite flashing, but some along.
Okay, so, so you know that from like the technical,
analysis side, right?
Through observations, yeah.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah.
But we have a way to describe
this is the parabolic stage,
but in other words,
parabolic means like crazy, fast.
It's like this.
That's what it does.
Yeah, I've seen you use that
in one of your,
on some of your tweets and stuff
and the ones in you annotated.
Okay, so this scandal,
what's it doing?
It's going down, up,
down, up, down, down, down.
It might finish it, right?
Mm-hmm.
And then it goes down, down, down, down, down, up, up, up, up, down, down, down, up.
Then this type of candle will be flash, flash, flash, flash, flash,
completely different ticket.
Okay, yeah.
Right?
We don't call it a candlestick pattern.
We don't call it a morning star, evening star.
That's for gay boys.
We just call it a parabolic.
You'll make much more sense to you when you start to observe it.
Yeah, okay.
We'll discuss also what's going on.
here in a moment's time.
But yeah, we only want to trade at these skewed book periods
where the probabilities are skewed in your favor.
Trading in those instances will push price in your direction almost instantaneously.
There's edge in trading in that environment, trading in that condition,
where the structures and the rules and the organization of the market
cause price to behave the certain type of way,
and you're just taking advantage of that behavior.
In other words, you now don't have to be a specialist about
where the UK economy is going to go
and who's going to push it there
you don't have to be right for a long time
you only have to be correct
about this very very short period of time
and almost instantaneously
price goes your way
all right so here
we're essentially discussing
the effects of understanding
microstructure we're able to define
where we want to trade
as long as we can take advantage of that
this edge there
you sold one of the models
largest issues
that most trading have
they have no edge
to trade anywhere
people will see
the selling
they might see
a market
structure break
short it
then realize
that overall
no real
structure was broken
and price
still continues
yeah
right
whereas if I'm
trading at the
exhaustion
you know
basically at the fin point
even if price
is going to end up
at this box
it will flash
I can short it
will flash
and then it will
finally reached it. I don't have to be right about the direction. I can be wrong about the
direction once, twice, as long as I traded that finish point in equity, I will always get
that initial response. So you're not a directional trader by any means? No, I can, I'll trade
both sides of the market. Yeah, okay. So like one day you wake up and like, oh, pounds trending
up or I'm just going to look for buys? No, I never do shit.
ever. Okay, that's cool.
Never.
I trade this behavior. I don't give two foxwoods going.
Okay.
Rather than me saying this is an option,
all I see as is multiple, multiple
exhaustions, price returning back
to the last, something that's called inventory,
price runs out,
sell liquidity is running away,
buy volume chasing, chasing, chasing, chasing,
becoming exhausted,
leaving that vacuum of bi-liquity behind,
where it requires much less selling to push price down.
And the same thing happened here is push.
And the same thing happened here is sell, sell, sell, sell.
Sellers got stretched out, left behind a vacuum, dried off.
It requires much less buying to push price off in this sentence.
Trading at least 10 points.
That's all I care of.
I could give to fucks about where price is going to go.
Really, I care more about just capturing.
So I'll show you some of the trades I talk today.
caught this
it was supposed to be
a 1.2 pip stop
by the time I got in
I could only
I was only mismanaged for about three pips
so it was a three pips stop
for me
I caught
I didn't catch that
I caught this
as you can see how my box did
I didn't catch this because it missed
it missed it slightly
in the morning I caught this
I also caught
this
How many trades did you take
Today, like I said
It's one of the best periods
Yeah
This stable, efficient environment
But I want to be active
This one, I went longer
I got to stop that
I long did it too early
I'm sure
I took a number train as well
Oh, your thinking
are floating everywhere
Oh, they've gone now
Yeah
I took this fucking train as well
That's short to hide there
I didn't take this
For one reason only
It didn't reach my land
And as you can see
Basically I wanted this
this come down into the core down there, yeah, back to its origin.
As you can see again, I missed it.
Okay, so, look, Price is super, super thin here.
It could respond on any of these levels, but the probability, as price travels out,
it leaves behind a vacuum, then you trade a vacuum, it will almost, it will basically
always finish, always finish.
Yeah, you know, I can see there at like 4.30 on the one-minute candles, there was a couple
massive candles there and then
yeah yeah
back up
these are event driven
there was a headline
always eventriven
something like that
but we don't want to get too much
into that for now at least
anyway
I've given you
for insight into
basically I haven't fully explained
why did the vacuum
I find there
and why this is more
prominent today at 2015
and less prominent
when there was EBS
as the main exchange
going into that basically
when there was more
volatility during EBS times
so this
you know
let me just put on that
so volatility refers to
um
pip distance
yeah yeah that's fine
today was
really volatile then
300 you said
in a day
it's been quite standard
you know all
recently
in the recent weeks at least
we had this huge run up
on Friday
on Monday
we had this huge
sell-off on Friday. He's on, he's on not small moves. A hundred pips up, 50, you couldn't
you, you could all be all these up which you want to, but that was a big volatility day.
18, 60, 50, 40, you know, so it's all been quite volatile, massive sell-up. And then before this
like last three weeks, we had, that's one day last week. That's one day last week. That was a massive
star. But before that, we actually, we had.
had like a more of a what I call inefficient environment, right?
So price was just drifting in one direction,
even though it moves a lot in that direction.
I can't say you didn't,
but we actually have the less direction of volatility
these days when prices in a higher timeframe
direction of move.
But we'll get into that when it's due time.
You have periods of volatility.
It can expand all expansion things and then periods of
relatively, it's always changing.
The state of volatility, at least for now,
hip distance travels. If this candle travels here and this candle travels there, there's more
volatility in that. There's a slightly different, I guess, interpretation of what volatility is,
is how much price is ticking and moving. But for now at least, we'll just call volatility this,
right? I know earlier I said price has been quite volatile today. I just mean in terms of how much
price moved, then you could have captured up to 300%
worth of stuff.
It's much easier
to capture 300 pips than it is to
just capture one view of
230 pips. It's two different
trains now. I don't know
if you've seen on Twitter. Sometimes I catch these
bigger moves, but I make more money
on days like this. Yeah, I remember that one time he had like
500 pips or something running on a
pound long, and I think is that
you posted, I think it was a week
before or something, you posted
that he was going to do it.
Yeah, but yeah, you're not on there anymore, so.
I'm long from WTI low.
Still?
From, you know, the days being up to here, we're going to go into the parabolic stage, and it did.
And then I said that I want to, I'm looking for a long position, on leveraged,
and I want to hold for multiple years, and I've got it, mom, I got it.
I wouldn't expect this to go mental.
It's not going to go to 100.
it's probably going to stay within this range between about 25, 30.
Can't use stuff like quickly change that, though?
Yeah, I was having the supply got, too much supply.
Again, it is, you know, I might happen.
I might be wrong.
It's just too cheap, not to push back,
and the way I see it is profound weakness in these areas.
I would expect it to eventually get about $70.
That's what I'll cut it.
doesn't have to be soon. That could range here for two years and then have one period where
I don't know, there could be a global production frenzy of, um, for example, I don't
fucking know. It could be any. I might be wrong. Price could sell off here. But probabilistically,
when, when price is cheap and there's so much, let's say, relatively thinness here,
relative thinness here, it kind of has to draw back in to find, the cell volume will always try
the selling is never unlimited the buying is never unlimited they almost always will dry
off unless there's some kind of irrationality in the market what do you mean by that um so it basically
it's a whole of the topic on reflexivity it's a theory called reflexivity um humans are in
naturally irrational um and the market can behave in that way so i'll give an example imagine
the true value
right, so reflexivity
is something that isn't necessarily
untrue, but it's not necessarily
true either, so if I said
to you it's raining outside and it was raining
that's a factual statement.
If I said to you
that the water gets you wet,
again, that's a factual statement. If I said
to you that that water is
hot like fire, again,
that is a, sorry, that's a
untrue state, that's a false statement.
So in either of those cases,
those were fractures.
Then you have certain beliefs
that are not necessarily factual,
they're not necessarily untrue either.
So one of them would be that yellow is a calming color.
It's an opinion, it's a bias.
Okay, yeah.
There's instances where certain risk assets
supported by other,
they can be supported by like behaviors
of governments of central banks, at least.
the central banks can create an environment
which makes me want to believe a certain
certain like, you know, makes me want to believe
for something. But avoid all that speculation.
There's certain times where I might hold a bias
about 500. I might say that it's cheap to own.
Well, if not cheap to own, I might say
that buying a company,
so I think Amazon's this to the recipe,
buying Amazon, you earn a,
higher dividend rate compared to borrowing the U.S. government money.
Factual statement.
Yeah.
So it's not a reflexive statement.
Okay.
And because of that fact that I just stated there,
there's a higher cash earning,
earning Amazon stock compared to borrowing the U.S. government money and bonds.
I might deem to say that Amazon as a company is a healthy company.
And because of that, I want to buy it.
So I go and buy it.
price goes up
that then confirms
my idea that Amazon is a healthy
company
because that
reinforces my idea
that Amazon is a healthy company
and buy more of it
and because price going up
because I'm buying more of it
reinforces that Amazon is a healthy company
I continue to buy more of it
but not just me the whole market
right
so now you have a dynamic where
even if Amazon isn't that health
Even if Amazon has structural issues with their debt, if Amazon has structural issues with how much money they're spending, right?
Market is latched on to this idea that price going up is confirmation of this, on this idea that the earnings reflect health,
and then that idea continues to cause buyers to come in, and this sentiment arises that Amazon has had to complete.
And essentially what happens is, even though the true value of Amazon,
may not be $2,000 per share,
price ends up going there
because of the irrationality of these traders
or these investors or these humans
which decide to latch on to a certain idea.
Okay, that makes sense now.
So it's called the theory of reflexivity.
It's the primary, I guess, theory behind why balls exist,
one of the most accurate one of my opinion.
But it's a George Soros theory,
Jew sympathizer.
So, yeah, there's time
where the market can behave quite irrationally
and price can continue going
this direction for a very, very long time.
But still, it doesn't go up on a straight line.
Amazon doesn't go like this.
It will, on a volume basis,
on an intraday basis at least,
it will have multiple periods
where the buying is super, super thin,
it has to draw back down
to find bidders again, et cetera, et cetera.
So even though there's very consistent buying,
it's not constant buying.
Right?
And again, I'm getting,
front of the head of myself and I just want to quickly go into the structure.
Last session, we got up until discussing that all the banks were connected through EBS.
EBS was where the prices were essentially forming and then the price changes on EBS were then reflected out to the market through the banks of this.
Yeah.
Right.
So here's customer segment.
Here's the interdealer market where there's multiple banks linked together.
A client goes along with Bank One.
Bank One then filters and hedges that risk on EBS, price changes on EBS, that's new price change.
And then obviously, all the other dealers update their prices to the rest of the market, to the customer sector.
So whoever has access to EBS sees the price change first, no?
Okay, so back then, really, the volatility would be coming from, this goes along with their dealer.
So he goes longer 100 million.
That $100 million, some of it the dealer takes on.
It takes the opposite side, but it's very, very unlikely to take the full position on.
So they decide to hedge that risk out on the EBS and try to offset, right?
That information leaks onto EBS, not only with the price change,
but why if all these are the dealers don't want to avoid selling
because this dealer wants to, you know, avoided selling 100 million to the client.
Rather, he didn't sell the $400 million.
He went out himself and tried to buy $100 million
to later sell to the client, right?
Information leaking about this large order
with the dealers want to go short.
They can result in the hot potato training,
causing price the extra buy income.
And the sell equity is almost not existent here.
A hot potato, that $100 million can get passed off
between all these dealers,
between these dealers, time and time and time again,
on and on and on and on,
until one of those dealers can offset it against one of their clients.
But let's just say, yeah, passed on there to there, to there,
then this fourth dealer had a client come in wanting to buy $100 million.
The dealer bought it, their client wants to buy it,
so they said what they just bought.
Yeah.
So finally that risk has been got, you know, the whole potato is training the stock.
But until they can externalize it, that might be at a much higher price as well.
You have to realize.
The problem with that is this.
guy was trying to fill 100 million, every
time he trades, he's
resulting in price jumping.
He's getting worse and worse prices. He wants to
fill at a desired price. Every time he tries
to get filled, the price goes away from his desired
price.
All I've talked about really
is clients going market order longer.
They could also go limit orders as well.
So imagine this client put a limit
order of 100 million at a certain price.
The dealer, in order to make sure that 100
million is filled, might also place an
identical 100 million bid MEPS all right in the same direction yeah because
client he wants to go along at 1.3145 yeah a hundred million rises right now at 3 1
1 right so price obviously has to drop he sorry 35 45 55 65 yeah it has to drop
26 pips for this hundred million to get triggered yeah no yeah if it drops 20
26 pips, the dealer's sell price is now hitting this guy's buy price.
He has to fill in for a hundred million short.
So maybe the dealer doesn't want to go 100 million short.
He also places an identical 100 million long order, long position on EBS.
To make sure if this guy's long order is triggered,
then the dealer also is triggered on a long order
and whatever he just bought, he can sell back to this kind.
and the dealer has a long position and a short position of 100 million each, he has no risk.
He's head.
Did you get it?
It will be identical in the same direction.
In this instance, imagine you're looking at the order book or the participants of EBS are looking at the order book
and they see a very, very large bit of step up and present itself in the book.
Now we're looking at the order book.
The bi-liquility is much, much beefier than the available sell equity, right?
Yeah.
because this one client placed a, you know,
let's you say it's a big bid,
he placed a very, very, very big bid
by limit order into the market.
So will all prices around it become thin?
No, no, no, no, that's what I'm saying here is,
imagine a large, a large customer places a very, very large
buy order, by limit order into the order on UBS,
through the Diva.
All the other participants can now see that buy liquidity is much thicker.
Yeah.
They're armed with the same information.
They know prices very unlikely to push past this big bidder.
Rather, they're expecting the big bidder to continue supporting prices.
They might even trade ahead of it.
Oh, okay, okay.
Right?
So if I said to you that houses will never ever drop it beneath 80K on your street or on somebody else's street.
There was a house on sale for 81K.
Would you buy it?
Yeah.
Assuming you'd want to buy it, yeah?
So if there's a very, very, very, very large bidder at 80K, you also want to fucking buy
81K.
You don't mind.
You might want to trade ahead of them, take an advantage of the order fuel, sorry, the information
arising from changes in the order book.
So changes in the order book, there is an information game being played.
And HFT traders alike, both the same fucking thing, high-frequency traders, they play
this information game on centralized assets like SEP-5MET, E-MITIC contract, S&P 500, gold, I guess,
oil, anything that's traded centrally on at least
the CME, there's going to be
I know oil and gold is a trade on CME, but there's going to be this
information game being played by high people's
to tradeers where if
there was a large sell order being placed
into the order book, they themselves
might be placing
for example a fake large sell order
in order to make it look like this
a big seller here.
So when other people try to sell ahead of it, they can remove the sell order.
So now that's gone.
And imagine before they place that sell order, they were already short from here.
They already market order sold here.
Yeah.
Do you get it?
So step one, market order sell here.
Step two, place a very, very large order here, make it seem like it's a big seller.
The effect is other sellers come through and push price down, trying to respond to this new information.
And the HFT system successfully manipulated prices by making it seem like the supply when there was none, that supply was fake for it.
It was nonexistent.
It was never intended to get filled.
So they can do that.
They can put the same.
It's illegal, but they do do it.
It's more sophisticated than this, by the way.
So in actuality, what they might do is.
So that's called scrutiny.
There's something else called layering with the book where they might place,
relatively small buy orders here and sell orders here.
Now, not knowing where price is going to go.
Let's just say somebody hits their bid,
and there's more volume to get filled behind that seller.
Obviously, this red arrow should go to the next buy order,
to the next buy order, to the next buy order, right?
But let's say in that time, the HFT was able to remove their own buy order
and sell at this buy order, so removing that as well,
and sell at this buy order
removing that as well
so now the
now the HFP system has
short positions here and here
and they sell it back
to this red arrow
that's not been filled here
at a cheaper price
so sorry they buy it back
to the seller at a cheaper price
essentially the HFP system
shorted there
brought it back there
riding the information
arising from this large
sell order that came through
they were only able to do that
because they could reach
the bi-liquity
they had faster than that red order
perlinson
imagine there was a
did you do that thing in school
where you had to run across
what do you call it
not circuit train then
when you're going to hold
you run from one end to the other to the other
to the other to the other
and every time you do it
I think every time you do two
I think that
called suicides.
Okay, so
I think it works
as you go forward
and back
and that's one
Yeah, that's one
yeah, yeah, yeah.
Now imagine
that's your distance
you have to travel
so you start going on one
I now know
you have to travel
all the latest back
but my
my call is only this big
so at a time
you do a full lap
I can probably complete
two, three, four
okay, yeah
now forget that that's distance
imagine that speed
so
it literally
this is how it works. Here's the exchange. Here's the high frequency trading system
servers. It might even be inside the exchange. The distance
here is only a couple of meters. You are on the opposite side of the world,
trading on the internet. So the way it works is you are here,
here's a data center a few thousand miles away from you. The exchange has
the server in the data center as well. Your broker has an exchange
in the data center as well and they're connected. You're connected
to the server of your broker.
When you go long, hits the server, hits your broker,
hits the exchange, when you're trading on a central asset,
when you're trading on a futures exchange.
And then that server information goes over the internet
and back to the exchange.
And that was a long position of one million
by order, market order by order,
to trade one million.
And it was only 500K there,
250k there and 250k there.
Price should go up three times, right?
Yeah.
One, two, three.
So all that information travels there,
which is thousands of miles.
When your order first starts to take that first 500k,
that's fine.
You might get filled for zero,
sorry, you might get filled for 2K within a few milliseconds.
Now this new volume, so, you know,
you just went long one million,
you're starting to take all over liquidity there.
Can you see how information has slowly changed?
You took 2K, the cell orders have now reduced.
There's only 498K available there.
That information now has to travel all the way.
But that new information
had only had to travel there to the HFCC system
much less distance.
And they know that there's a large order on the way
because continuously two gets filled,
three gets filled, four gets filled,
fire guessful talking billions of a second nanosecond billions and within that time frame this
hfd system can also go along remove the available liquidity before you before you before your
orders continue before your orders fully fill jump the queue ahead of you take this liquidity
so now the the the the hfd system's gone long for example 498k plus so basically
998k they've gone long you follow me and imagine they then resold it to you here
so what does that mean you try to go along a million when you should have got filled 500k there
you should have got 50 or 250 there over three pips for example but as you were filling the first part
of your order they jumped the queue ahead of you to call the liquidity there took all the liquidity there
took all the liquidity there and we sold it to you at the 40 pin so you just got slipped to four pips because they were
able to reach that liquidity faster than me.
Haven't they made money as well?
Yeah, yeah, that's how they're model.
That's how they make money.
They don't provide, you know, the HFT lobby,
so those who influence regulators in the government
who have hired the lobbying firms,
they would say that HFT systems
place loads and loads of sending limit orders
by labor orders in the market,
loads and loads of that. But the only place
in limit orders at more expensive prices
after they already took inequality
ahead of it.
Yeah. So they shorted there, and then we bought back down there.
So in other words, they only are willing to be active in the market if they can reach the liquidity energy.
If there was heavy, heavy, heavy selling one direction, they will not be present in that market.
These small orders that they place, by very, very small orders will disappear.
there will be no liquidity,
holding equity on one side of the market.
That's where you get flash prices in the USIP by 100.
That's where you can have like weeks of selling.
Obviously there's times where they put some liquidity
at the end of the day, etc.
But for the most part, in at least 2010,
it was a flash crash here, the Dow Jones.
I think it crashed like 9%.
It was top 1 trillion that day
within about 5, 10 minutes.
And it was primarily a function
of these HFD systems, not only removing bioliquity, but also turning into sellers.
You get it?
And that, again, is them in those heavy one-sided volume environments, avoiding that diverse
selection, so they know that there's heavy selling going on.
There's bioliquity there.
They jumped the queue, sell there, part of eye over there.
So this arrow has a travel over.
And then there's more selling coming through.
They jump the queue, sell here.
And then this arrow has a travel further to the next area with this biolkidavis.
Yeah.
Do you get it?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So when it should have been one and two selling, they're now forcing.
They consistently, consistently destabilized markets under these event-driven states,
when there's heavy, heavy volume on one side because of some event.
It doesn't always have to be an event.
It could be in 2010, the flash flash of 2010.
It was not an event.
It was just heavy volume from one firm, a stupid pension fund,
started to sell a huge amount of SEP 500 contracts in a crazy, ridiculous way.
And that kind of caused these HFP systems for Haywire.
Virtue Financial,
Virtue Financial, which is a,
it's a HVP firm owned by a prominent head, yeah,
for a hedgeman manager.
These guys had one losing day over, I think, about 1,100 trading days.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, I think it would be discussed in this.
Yeah, so they can only do that
because they have such a, such a edge, you know,
a technological edge of everybody else
where they can take liquidity and jump the queue.
Again, it's like this example.
Here's the cinema brief.
You're here and here's your friend
and here's another friend.
I jumped the queue.
I buy all the tickets
and I resell them at a higher price.
Right?
I jump the queue, you're pissed off.
And then I sell them a higher price.
You're even more pissed off.
And maybe by this point
you've already bought your popcorn
and all that shit so you kind of forced to go.
But, you know, by that point I'm saying it,
when you place a market order,
you have to accept that price.
yeah that's true that's given to you um one point i'll raise here that example where i said
998k they'll go along is bullshit they only really go along one lot at that time they trade so
they trade smaller than i do really yeah they might trade one lot a thousand times oh the only
trade they only trade very very very small they do not trade large but you know yeah yeah so
and S&P 500 on futures exchanges, the average volume was much higher, but I think it dropped
down to about one lot. One standard lot is the average volume traded on SIP 500, I think in a 20.
This is what you call, you know how I said, here's the exchange, yes, it's the Chicago
and Burkentile Exchange. They have their own servers, and then the HF, the HFP Edge Fund is
directly located next to it. They're located much closer than you are, which are halfway across
the world, and let over internet latency barriers, right?
you go long, that long information has to be updated in prices, and that updated information
has to be sent out to the market. Before it reaches you, it's reached them, and they can reach
back and reach back and forward and back and back, you know, well before you've reached through
you've received that information. It's crazy. It's a cheat, but it's crazy. And that's the kind
of level these markets operate on, and we're here trying to use. Yeah, when you said it's the hardest thing
now, I understand.
Bullish Maserobu, oh, yeah,
we'll buy it. These markets,
by the time that fucking candles form,
these guys have been able to trade
thousands of times. Absolutely
ridiculous. They also,
from the exchange, which is kind of,
the exchange is supposed to be a referee.
They should favour nobody. But the exchange
has offered these guys
like volume rebates. If they trade X amount
volume, they give them cash back on the commissions.
They offer them very very nice commission
rates. I
would argue, but you know what, that's bullshit. You don't have to argue it. A Bloomberg
researcher, or a Bloomberg, I guess he's a researcher and a journalist, he wrote a book
on that guy was in name, Nav Singh. He was prosecuted for the 2010 flash, although
he didn't cause it. Within that book, he basically said that many of these exchange
operators, the directors of the exchanges, also have financial interests with the actual
So it's called crony, I think it's called cornism, when you like favour, you know, I don't know what it's called, but
basically what I'm saying to you is all corrupt at the highest levels of these exchanges, where the
price is going to be happens for the largest contract or the most liquid futures contract in the
world. S&P 500 is called e-mini, right? There's high, high levels of unfair advantage, you know,
a lack of regulation around these type of
entities, H&T firms.
We have the capacity to make it more
expensive for you to trade. And now if I ask
you this question, the market's job is
to find you a seller if you're a buyer.
But if the market structure
is causing that seller to be more expensive
than it should be, the market's not doing a good
job. And it's
that exact inefficiency,
or the effect of that exact inefficiency, which
in my opinion is with this edge.
If the market did this job, there would be no
because if if the GDP USD price is reflecting all the available information that's present
and the bid and ask then that price is right you know there's this theory out there
called the efficient market hypothesis which which like certain dick is that will say
that markets are impossible to be basically right in other words they say that
SP500 has continued to grow since the 1920s and it's never stopped
And that rate of growth is impossible to be if you're an active trader, buying and selling
currencies, or buying and selling S&P by country.
So you can just buy S&Pan countries, leave it and let it arise.
That's called passive investing, or it can be an active investor and basically trade.
The official market hypothesis says it's impossible to be, you know, the long-winded performance
or the long-run performance of S-Pap hundred because it always reflects all the available information
president. In other words, what it's saying is the price of SB
Boundred is always right. If it's here, this is reflecting all the
available information about the health of the underlying
companies. It's reflecting all the available information in regards
to buy limit orders, sell limit orders, volume hitting the book
all the time. But I say that's untrue, at least in markets
where you have HMT firms eliminating the equity that was really
there and cause a price to stretch out, right? Because if the H&T system, you know, you're going
long at this price, they're removing the liquidity from these three prices and we're selling it to
you here. They're causing price to jump to this level and trade, you know, causing your volume to
essentially stretch out. Does that not, does that not basically the efficiency in percentage
your trade
and percentage in your trade
basically not present
right
them driving prices higher
systematically and then
as your volume
because what's going on here is your volume
is a driving factor you go longer
million you're trying to find
sell equity in there taking a sell equity
and we're offering it to you a higher and higher
prices in small amounts
so it's essentially
causing price of one higher once you're one million
dries are, they offered you that sell liquidity in small amounts throughout this duration of this,
of this buying, and it resulted in, again, a veritable new traded move, where in reality, you should
have been able to find all of that sell liquidity in about three price levels. If your one million
trade was facilitated within this area here, price could continue trading in this area and basically
finding and matching
sellers with buyers
and buyers with sellers
as long as
they're selling and buy equity
in this range. That can continue
happening. Then the market is reflecting
more accurately at least is true
by them. But if I if a
HFE system comes in and
removes the year
not because they have a certain view
of S&P 500 but because
they're just trying to explore your water flow
causing price to reach out
that's then creating this move
which is not a real move
it's actually a dislocation
from its true value
the true value bear in mind was
price matching sellers and price
together within this range
if there was no exploiting factor
yeah that's correct
right so I know I'll pause there for a minute
but this point I'm trying to raise
this dislocation affects
price running further than it should
is a function of behaviours
of certain participants in the market
which caused these
thinly traded moves
where in reality
if they did not behave like that
you should be able to find
that liquidity where you wanted
where you saw it
and the market can continue
to certate and trade
wherever these buyers and sellers
those buyers and sellers
are likely going to be presenting themselves
because they take a certain view of the market
that then is the market
reflecting accurately
the SP 500
information as present
worldwide
right but again
just to finalize
If this this motherfucker comes in, remove these sellers, we sell it to a higher and higher and higher prices, making price jump out, then this move is more manufactured than it is natural.
It's not reflecting information in the market.
It's more a function of the exploitive behavior of this particular participant, which should be regulated, but it's not.
But the effect of it is, the market is not inefficient anymore.
it's not perfectly efficient.
It's at times almost very, very inefficient.
And it's this inefficiency that we know the effect of it.
Basically, once your volume dries off,
most likely, price will continue to draw back in,
back to where the buyers are,
and then this gives us edge.
We can exploit this inefficiency.
Another example of inefficiency is,
imagine on venue one,
Bitcoin was on offer for 10K.
So you could buy it for 10k
10kk. On venue 2
was being brought for 10.1 can.
The best best offer is actually
a positive spread here.
You could buy here,
instantaneously sell it
and make $100
per Bitcoin time and time
and time and time again, free of charge.
If me and you rent a sit, here's a tennis court.
Here's the umpire.
Federer scores a point.
Information, yeah?
the umpire
receives that information
plugs it into his computer
and then the rest of the world knows
you are home known
on your team
now imagine
before the umpire
could put the
the federal point
into his computer
I was on the phone to you
and you placed a bet
that federal score of point
the odd makers
have updated their pride
have updated their odds
they can only update their odds
when the umpire puts
their information in
imagine the umpire is very slowly
the fat old backs. That inefficiency, that slowness of updating information is exploitable by me and you.
I just tell you the information faster than the umpire updates it. You place the you place the bet and you're
guaranteed to make money free or charge. You go into price actually anyway. I want to introduce you to
use a few things. So all the principles around price, which is stuff like variable volume
flow. I'm going to discuss how centipers are constant. There's a PDF for it. You can go
through it if you want to show you a minute.
The next session, why we need to discussively finalise is how
actually you can finish this off now. So, right,
EBS, you've got Tennis, EBS.
Electronic brokerage system.
Connecting dealers together, allowing them to trade against each other,
go into this scale. But the problem was information needs to
walk them from clients onto EBS.
All the people can respond and they can respond. They can result in
in skewed books, uh, dealers hop-taire trading, more
volatility than they shouldn't be because too much information to get out. Then Prime
Brokridge came about allowing customers, clients, to access quotes from modular banks, the best
bit best offer. There was a new provision by EBS that they would also let, they change
the rules around the EBS, basically. It was not an interdita market anymore. I think in like
1998, I think 2000, one of those years, EBS changed the walls and basically said that Prime
brokerage clients can now post liquidity directly onto EBS through the bank, of course, as long
as they have planned coverage. Because what prime brokerage essentially is, the bank already has
credit relationships with Bank 2 and Bank 3 and Bank 4, right? The Prime brokerage client gets
to trade on those credit relationships through Bank One's name. So imagine I have your, you know,
so yeah, probably a great example, but imagine you have a good credit rating, I pay you to take
loan out for me and as long as I keep a percentage of the margin there of that loan all the time
you're fine with doing that you're letting me ride your credit accessibility yeah
the potential the banks doing and in turn obviously the private crush clients get access to all these
quotes so eBS finally let third party non-banks trade directly on eBS remember what i said what
EBS is the prices will be
made there. So
volume from client
goes to dealer, goes to
EBS, because the dealer's hedging
there. EBS obviously
forms the prices because the dealer
tries to find equity, et cetera, et cetera.
Price changes, then that
new information is reflecting
back out to clients in the market.
So the first price changes were happening on
EBS. Guess what? These
motherfuckers did those HFT
firms to get it.
They're the third party non-banks who started to access EPS, see the price for information
update information ahead of the rest of the market, and they were able to do two things.
They were basically trading in the same way that we just discussed exploiting Bank One, Bank,
two, Bank, Three, Bank, Four's prices with speed, right?
They were able to lay the box, scoop the box, they had the faster technological capacity.
So they were able to do the HFT type behaviours on EBS itself.
Secondly, they also then started to resell that liquidity.
So they could see price changes on EBS.
They could see that Bank 1, Bank 2, Bank 3, Bank 4 has limit orders and sell it.
And limit orders at these prices, that's the best bid best offer.
They could also approach liquidity there.
And because these guys have the capacity to look, if they have a buy order here, that's $1 million.
if 20k of that starts to get eaten
what's left over?
980k yeah
they have the capacity to remove
980k sell ahead
and then buy back down here
front one the rest of the market
so what this allowed them to do is
show more competitive bids and offers
to tighten the spread of because they
don't mind having more expensive bid prices
and cheaper sell prices
because they have that speed advantage
to get it.
So what they did by posting equity on EBS,
they then started to post
tighter bidding offers on EPS
and start to sell
how the bank sells equity,
this bank sell liquidity,
the third party non-bank market makers,
which would basically HFT firms,
started to sell cheaper quotes,
tightest prints.
What's happening here?
Basically, these third party non-bank market makers
are taking market share away from
So it's the HFTs that are doing that.
Yes.
Because look, EBS was once
I entered the platform.
You could only be a bank and trade on the EBS.
Yeah, yeah.
Right.
And then prime brokerage service
allowed non-bank market makers,
sorry, non-bank clients,
like a large hedge fund,
to post volume and trade on EBS directly,
connect to it directly.
EBS was the primary
price formation.
exchange that's where the prices were being formed before they were showed the rest of the market
there was a time difference price shows a price formed here takes a half a second to update it
the less in the market that 0.5 a second is maybe exploded one you get it yeah and that's what
they did not necessarily no so these guys already invested heavily in the tech side they
they had the technological capacity to help price these guys itself so
Think about it. Bank One will only post a spread for one pip because obviously they're trying to capture that one-pip spread, but maybe if they posted a 0.1-pip spread, you know, price is moving too much and they wouldn't be able to hedge that list. Did you get it?
So put it this way. With a one-pip spread, if I quote that to you, you can sell here, you can buy here.
Price can move 0.9 pips against me, and I still haven't lost up.
Yeah.
With a 0.1 pip spread,
price can only move 0.1 pips
and that's it you break even.
You get it.
For me, if I'm dealing
with a 0.1 pip spread,
price can only be 1 pip and I say,
and I have next to a losing position.
The HFD firms,
they can, with a 0.1 pip spread,
with 0.5 pips spread,
they can hedge their risk,
they can get out of positions
because they have that speed advantage.
You get it?
Yeah.
So they were able to post tighter quotes and resell tighter quotes to the rest of the market.
They just keep on doing it and doing it.
And now if you're a client, I said to you, if you know you're looking for quotes, these banks have a two-pips spread each.
This HFT firm has a 0.5 pips spread.
Which one would you want to buyer?
Yeah.
Or trade with that means.
These guys would offer very competitive quotes.
Do you get it?
Yeah.
So now volume is trading with HFTs.
It's not trading with the banks.
So market share with being stolen.
Imagine I came onto the largest shotters in your ends,
and I took their block away from them.
I have stolen market share from them.
There were certain things that these banks did in the following years
that brought back.
One of them being investing heavily in the tech side.
That's why I know you don't have traders at banks
to anybody in either the Big Four accounting firms,
so KPMG,
fuck, what's the other one?
So if you speak to anybody
the Big Four Accounting Forms or the large,
banks, commerce bank,
Deutsche Bank,
etc.,
they will tell you
for free
that the business
analysis side,
the business analyst
side,
the tech side,
quantitative,
like,
lies who fucking got
some crazy
max degrees,
they're fucking just
Chinese people
with crazy glasses.
They are getting
the most comparative
wages compared to
at Burley Traydown
who speaks that
that weird English,
that Essex that English.
You get it.
Yeah. Most people think that, you know, most people have this association that Worm, FX, London banks, Wall Street as well, they're like those World for Wall Street traders. They're not anymore.
Wolfram Wall Street, obviously, they were stock sellers in any way, but people think that's what training is now. It's not.
You more have whole floors and teams dominated by just these technologically sunny guys because the banks had to fight back against these HHS.
to maintain market share and invest heavily in their own technology and capacity to stop
getting picked off. Imagine here you have an order book, right? Here's a sell order and here's
a buy order. Imagine every single time you went to buy, that sell order disappears. What can you
do? Maybe, maybe you need to get to that sell order quicker. Maybe you need to trick whoever's
making that cell order disappear, right? Maybe you need to place heavy, heavy sell orders yourself,
make that guy
start selling
and then remove your sell load
and buy it back
at cheaper price against them
right so
banks started to buy it back
but we'll leave that for now
HR private brokerage service allowed access
to EDS the primary exchange
for price formation
these guys are technologically savvy
and had the necessary capacity
to exploit not only dealer
inefficiencies
the slowness of dealers
but also price out
price them out
offer competitive rates
to the rest of the market
and start to take Mockishie away from them.
I'll leave that.
If you have any questions, then you know.